<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Chris DeCarolis</title>
    <link>https://dpeng817.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Chris DeCarolis</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 08:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dpeng817.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Two Weeks of Nothing</title>
      <link>https://dpeng817.github.io/posts/doing_nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dpeng817.github.io/posts/doing_nothing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had an exciting few months. I went on a many-month anticipated family trip, switched jobs, and moved in with my partner. The latter two were concurrent. Now, I have about two weeks before my new job begins. Two weeks of nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m somewhat financially solvent, enough that I could consider going on a long trip. But I wanted to take this time to explicitly do nothing exciting, mostly because I just felt exhausted by the logistics the past few months required. I didn’t want to figure anything out ahead of time. So I set out with more or less no plan for what to do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t seem like a big deal, but ask yourself - when was the last time you had two uninterrupted weeks with no objective? For me, it’s winter break during freshman year of college - almost 9 years ago. After that, I got my first internship, and the career flywheel got going. I expect many folks at a similar career stage to be similar. Once you are out of the winter/summer break routine of grade school, especially if you live in a city&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, your time becomes mostly spoken for unless you take explicit action&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  Even if you experience a layoff / firing, there&amp;rsquo;s the duress of needing to find a new job, which is an implicit objective guiding your decision making.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nothing-time imposes a different set of constraints from routine guided by objective - the time is all yours to do with what you will, but, there&amp;rsquo;s a very fixed end date. This seems to have resulted in a lot of creativity and energy. I feel almost ravenous for new ideas and experiences. To use an AI analogy (sorry), it feels like I’m undergoing a big backprop step for the first time in a while, where my brain’s weights are changing quite actively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the free time so far, I’ve made this website, learned vim beyond layman terms (previously I didn’t even know what visual mode was), established a consistent meditation practice, done a lot of vibe coding (another post on that later), and done a bunch of random stuff I’ve been thinking about trying but haven’t gotten around to (trying lap swimming, doing the SF crosstown trek, going to concerts and staying till the end), Overall having a blast and feeling quite productive. Despite not starting out with any concrete goals, they naturally arose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would love to be able to “enter” this state more often. I think that a big inducing factor was having the “nothing time” &lt;em&gt;directly following&lt;/em&gt; a tumultuous period. You often learn a lot of implicit lessons in these periods, but if you don’t pause to soak in the insights, it&amp;rsquo;s easy for the insights to get lost. There&amp;rsquo;s also something probably &amp;ldquo;unseating&amp;rdquo; about tumult that might prime you for more change.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think you realistically need at least 5 days (two days of rest, two days of creativity, one day to get ready for life again) to make a period like this meaningful, and ideally it’s scheduled right after something impactful and a bit difficult (like the completion of a major project). Give it a try, you might be surprised how impactful it is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because of the size of your expanded network living in a city, it becomes easy to get tied up in constant social obligations, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re a people-pleaser by nature. Not saying that folks who don&amp;rsquo;t live in cities don&amp;rsquo;t experience the same thing!&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think that: (advancing your career, living in a city, having a big network) is well worth it as a tradeoff over having more free time. It&amp;rsquo;s just worth noting the reality of the tradeoff.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>https://dpeng817.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dpeng817.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dpeng817.github.io/cdecarolis_resume.pdf&#34; download=&#34;cdecarolis_resume.pdf&#34;&gt;download&lt;/a&gt;  my cv or &#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dpeng817.github.io/cdecarolis_resume.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;view&lt;/a&gt;  it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading</title>
      <link>https://dpeng817.github.io/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dpeng817.github.io/reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;recommendations&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Recommendations&lt;span class=&#34;heading__anchor&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#recommendations&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Books/series/writings that I think are worth your time, in no particular order. Obviously opinions are my own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;toggle-description&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;toggle-trigger&#34;&gt;Malazan Book of the Fallen - Steven Erikson&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;toggle-content&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A ten book epic fantasy series. It&amp;rsquo;s the best one out there, if you have the time and energy to commit. The first book is the worst (and it&amp;rsquo;s still good, especially when you compare it to the debut novel of something like Wheel of Time). Every other book varies between very good and incredible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Malazan demands a lot from you. It throws you into an entirely new world without any fanfare, leaving you to piece together what&amp;rsquo;s going on. There&amp;rsquo;s probably more characters introduced (and killed) than any other book series I&amp;rsquo;ve read. Each book is hundreds to thousands of pages. In return, it treats the reader with intense respect. There are no easy wins or unearned emotional payoffs. There is so much anguish, humor, life, death, &lt;em&gt;humanity&lt;/em&gt; poured into these novels. It is simultaneously the most engrossing and least escapist fantasy series I can imagine. Please go read it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;toggle-description&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;toggle-trigger&#34;&gt;Realm of the Elderlings - Robin Hobb&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;toggle-content&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A 16 book epic fantasy series, told in discrete chunks separated by long stretches of time. I think you really do need to read them all to get the full emotional payoff, and that&amp;rsquo;s a somewhat hard ask. I would say the best sub-series are (in this order):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tawny Man trilogy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Liveship Traders&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fitz and the Fool&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been said before; Fitz is one of the best developed protagonists in fantasy. You experience so many parts of his life through these novels. Fitz is also a very traumatized person in a world without therapy; being in his head for long stretches of time can honestly be difficult,&#xA;and there are moments where I simply had to put the book down. It is Fitz&amp;rsquo;s intense bonds with other characters (specifically the Fool) that make the novels so unique, and worth reading. Because of how well developed Fitz is, the highs and lows of these relationships feel very consequential, and quite realistic. I found it absurdly engaging, and felt book withdrawal for nearly a week after finishing it.&#xA;The first trilogy is probably required reading for everything else to make sense. The Rain Wilds are&amp;hellip; not my favorite, unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;toggle-description&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;toggle-trigger&#34;&gt;This is Water - David Foster Wallace&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;toggle-content&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s short, you can find it with a quick google search. The brain loves threes - and &amp;ldquo;this is water&amp;rdquo; is now burned into my brain. I could wax poetic about it, but I think you&amp;rsquo;ll get more by just reading.&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;toggle-description&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;toggle-trigger&#34;&gt;The Left Hand of Darkness - Ursula LeGuin&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;toggle-content&#34;&gt;First of all, what a badass title. Second of all, I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it was written in 1969(!). It lays bare the lie (excuse?) that old science fiction is necessarily pulpy. The ideas feel so fresh and provocative even today, maybe especially today, and the world is so well realized. All of the Ekumen novels are excellent (maybe with the exception of &amp;ldquo;The Word for World is Forest&amp;rdquo;), but if you were going to read just one, this should be it.&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;toggle-description&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;toggle-trigger&#34;&gt;One Piece - Eiichiro Oda&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;toggle-content&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s intimidatingly long, but if you read it, it goes quick.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One Piece is so weird. A manga about pirates, where nobody ever does any pirating once. It goes off the rails instantly from its intended plot and then expands out in every possible direction. At one moment, it&amp;rsquo;s goofy, and two minutes later you&amp;rsquo;re in a flashback where the main villain&amp;rsquo;s parents die tragically. This duality is suffused through every aspect of One Piece, and honestly it might offend the sensibilities of some readers. Women  are drawn with absurd unrealistic body proportions, and yet their actual stories are filled with nuance. Trans characters are portrayed in extreme charicature, and yet there is an unspoken dignity to the way the series treats them emotionally. The scope is ever expanding, and yet the world feels so &lt;em&gt;connected&lt;/em&gt;. I hesitate to tell you too much in advance, but One Piece, again and again, delivers on its ambition. It looks like it will stick the landing. Go catch up before it ends.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://dpeng817.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dpeng817.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can reach me at cdecarolis&amp;lt;two&amp;gt;&amp;lt;eight&amp;gt;&amp;lt;nine&amp;gt; at gmail &amp;lt;dot&amp;gt; com.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
